[Music]
so hi there hi there event ology of
ontology yeah
I skipped all the small talk stuff yeah
even deep that would like an almost
French accent of ontology the moment it
happens to me I have ontology yeah I
don't mind that all your Canadian your
excuse of ontology is the opposite of
Normandy ology so when it comes to doing
history and doing religion you you
obviously have a fundamental story this
is a story circular time so if you say
Mircea Eliade of the great
anthropologist in the 20th century they
do it alright about circular times the
fundamental time that you being
suffering according to so you know every
new year there'll be a new world so
every year is the same so everything is
repeated constantly this is called
circular time and it's actually how time
was understood for hundreds of thousands
of years by you being so there was
really no reason for us to look at time
differently from that and this ties in
with what we talked about before you
know which is no mythology can is one
thing came to my mind does that have
anything to do with eternal return
yes exactly there's even a Elliot book
called the myth of the eternal return we
also know this expression from Nietzsche
of course all right the eternal return
means that everything returns to the
same place and then it just repeats
itself and this comes from the origin of
religion where every human behavior was
seen as some kind of imitation of the
gods like every actor we do a God would
have done first
when elderly or your parents and
eventually you and and this of course
ties in with biology and how children
are pre-programmed to imitate and mimic
their parents and of course all your
beings when we call the times sure are
but um Missy Elliott writes about this
like the myth of the eternal return is
fundamental to human beings
this is numerology because the the
nammed ology being the teaching of human
beings as creature constantly on the
move means that the nomadic tribe the
sociologists we call it no work
this original nomadic tribe it's on the
move all the time but it's also on the
move in a circular way it returns to the
same place probably because of the
nomads we're moving according to the
seasons so this is fundamental circular
turn now what happens is that there is
obviously traces of ontology already in
the nomadic tribe especially Seamus
would practice something that would be
similar to ontology there's certainly
something in the military so if you were
involved in hunting or warfare you'd be
involved in an ontology but we would end
the day you die so once you transcend it
and transferred everything onto your
your heritage onto your sons and it
would all be repeated anyway it'd still
be within this sort of the eternal
return of the same but what happens we
start a settle down about ten thousand
years ago is that because we don't move
any longer we started to move the world
of ideas mm-hmm and we can't call that
nammed ology because once you start them
over the world of ideas then things do
not necessarily have to be the same
every year
so this tie seems especially masculine
fantasy of the son being different from
the father and if a loss of always has
written a lot about this issue of the
loose his most famous book is called
difference repetition deforms one
tradition from the 1960s it was probably
stock truth aces originally but it's an
absolutely brilliant book where
discusses me just returned returned are
the same and that sets misunderstood
because what Nietzsche means is that
with every loop every term it is
slightly different from the last term so
there's a small difference this what's
called difference repetition there's a
small difference with every loop in the
eternal return and this difference
creates the potential for a different
world
this is the birth of linear time or a
phallic time so what happens with
Zoroastrianism which is the first one to
formulate this idea he estado roster
about three thousand several years ago
formulas are lead and built on linear
time alone and saying that cyclical time
is delusional
linear time is way more interesting or
phallic time meaning we can create
civilization and civilization Alba sees
that we improve on everything we improve
on the ideas we improve on the
technologies all the time we improve on
the text we've improve on the art we've
proven everything we human beings do we
get more and more advanced to be more
more sophisticated what we do it's not a
we change so astros adamant that we
don't change its our environmental
changes and we change with it
so then process is no longer just
process it becomes process and event and
the word first is an event yes and yeah
you probably know by now that's the
working title then you work in title of
the book you could call the new book
numerology and of ontology but I think
process and then export sounds because
it's exactly what it is so
so even ecology arrives in history
obviously this is also happened in India
China that there are traces of this of
course and always some of course a
Shiley some in India so there are
several Indian mystical schools as well
who go into this idea that there is
something that leaves the circular time
the Sun is different from the Father one
loop is different from the last one and
this difference in itself creates the
possibility of acquainting a better
world hmm so the dream of creating a
better world arrives and without linear
time we couldn't have that dream right
but the two things are happening aren't
they that we're creating a better world
and we're also destroying at the same
time right there's a design and a
creative process happening
simultaneously right well I'm not sure
we are destroying
we are obviously living in times that
are convinced that we are not Bach
elliptic times but having looked a lot
into Bjorn Lomborg work recently you
know the Danish guy who is fantastic by
the way if you want to check out
environmentalists and then check the
facts and go e-coat opium you should
definitely check up you're in Lombok
he's amazing but your long bar gets done
a lottery
search on this and actually come back
with the facts and and these days is
essentially that apocalyptic astareal
experience right now is unfounded and
over them but in any case in any case of
ontology becomes a parallel way of doing
narrative next to norman ology and i
would argue it's not that one of them is
right no one's wrong i think we need
both yeah he's gonna unify east and west
that's the phallic and the mid shirk
matriarchal again is it yep
yes phallic and metrical it's exactly
what this is so the metrical way of
events is no mythology and the phallic
way lens is of ontology so so what we
have then is that we have the linear
time religions coming hours or astron
ISM I of course regard Judaism and
Christianity Islam has increased
vulgarize Asians of the originals or
ester religion I'm still a fan I do this
I'm not much of a fan of Christianity
and certainly not much of that when it
comes to Islam but but that's of course
because Christianity and Islam are just
popular I say shion's and way more
superficial than Zoroastrianism and
Judaism work and if you want to
understand why then sore ass tourism and
Judaism have the Bard
absolutely intact that means there's no
direct connection between human beings
in God and that is absolutely
fundamental to religion whereas
Christianity Islam promises no there are
no no limits left God and man are no
directly connecting one another and of
course the vulgar version of that is
that man becomes God which Christianity
and God becomes man
and that's Islam contrary to what you
think so um it's the child god thing
right the idea the child of God or one
of the same thing and the whole the
whole personal no matter ology did you
would be a child and want to become an
adult and you become and hopefully
parent and then you become an elder and
if you Doug did well and don't lucky it
could be a for father or for mother
people looked up to you become what are
the lesser gods eventually so so this
whole chain of transcendence is that
human beings were foster to live within
the
tribe disappeared and we Christianity in
Islam we basically told no there's no
difference between child and God at all
it's not only there's no difference in
man and God but such interesting
childhood God mm-hmm and this exactly
saw in Christianity running told the
problems that they did they're agnostic
religions and Gnosticism is to began in
here so going back to surrealism in
surrealism you cannot separate body and
mind but rather you use separate child
and grown-up and you separate grown-up
and elder he a separate elder and priest
or say to you separately since age from
God
and then there's a whole chain here of
reporting you could call it a hierarchy
it's very very important to stay with
now the beauty of man and this is the
reason why so a stem is the first
tolerant universe religion and why are
universal human rights today originated
from Surat Annisa
not only linear time but also universal
human rights are originally personal
innovations the reason for this is that
so raster didn't really want to separate
event ology and phenomenology he didn't
claim like the Christians and the
Muslims did that we must forget about
circular time time has stopped because
of certain occasions Muhammad rode into
Mecca Jesus died on the cross certain
events have changed things forever
there's no more circular time and
they'll be an industry that's kind of
maybe the Abrahamic contempt towards
paganism err but it is it is originally
a mistake in mimicking was arrested ISM
because it's or asterism you keep both
of ontology and no madala G and the
reason we kept both and the traces you
find well you kept both is that no
morality is being kept as polytheism
mmm-hmm intolerant is being kept as mana
fizzing and it's or Astron ism these
were just different layers of thinking
just like they are in Hinduism the
different layers of thinking
monotheism is for the priests and the
split fellows is of course for the
military but for the rest of the tribe
for the rest of the community policies
mr. natural religion we can call this
the worship of the lesser gods and the
lesson
gods of the gods you dare to go to as a
human being hmm these are the Saints
these are the celebrities these are the
idols these are the icons the stirs yeah
this time well this stars these are the
people you can identify woods they're
your older sibling so your older
brothers your older sisters we see them
return today in a big way with a
youtubers you know how much I love the
youtubers but I think the youtubers are
gonna take over the world in the 2020s
they're gonna kill politics is gonna
kill academia they're gonna kill oh the
industry haven't they already well they
are fast there dude that fast and
PewDiePie is probably the most powerful
person on the planet right now nobody
gets that but I love the youtubers
because the youtubers are the
reinstatement of the lesser gods mm-hmm
demigods yeah I call them lesser gods I
think less of gods the great name so
this is what politics is all about this
is what's beautiful with a female
spiritual fantasy with family religion
magical realism magical religion really
is the religion of the saints it is the
original the direct axis and while they
is because the female mind comes up with
those ideas it's it's a magical way of
seeing the world it's also very circular
daughters have no need to be different
from the mothers they give birth to
different children anyway why would they
be different why would they race the
children's any different from what the
mothers did you don't have to know the
idea that you're different from your
parent is between son and father it's
it's a phallic fantasy that's I haven't
all of these tied to the phallic I want
know it all are you beautiful is tied to
the metrical and this of course my
Hinduism ultimately it's very magical
religion whereas you've got a lot of
Indian mysticism that's phallic or you
get shot ISM but Hinduism in itself is
magical I don't problem with that all I
think the relationship between you're
wrong in Indian religion is very very
very very important because what the
Iranians understood the roster
understood the way so rationalism is
unique if you guys understood that we
can separate of ontology and turn it
into religion for the military and for
the priests said become phonic and we
cannot have a separate religion that
celebrates the woman
the child the delivery station for the
man and that religion becomes magical
and that's exactly why in the Persian
Empire
none of the moments of the celebrated
Ahura Mazda and he celebrated his foot
follows their monotheistic monoface was
invented then at the same time get pom
system and it was prevalent it was
everywhere you know in the bazaars in
the streets downs little just people
will worship the different local gods
they had goddesses and gods and these
gods and goddesses reflected in the same
with it le odd and gerard of discussing
when they reflected an understanding of
the world where the gods would guide you
and speak for you and help you and
support your whatever you did and you
had something to mimic mm-hmm yeah I
think for people to mimic something they
have to have a directly a ship without
God yeah if that's one of the lesser
gods you should know my knowledge is all
about also you mimic you mimic the gods
when you're younger right in a sense
maybe I'll see your mimic your parents
your parents then mimic the priests and
the sages and the priests and say just
mimic the gods meaning when you're
mimicking a lesser God you're mimicking
a priest or a sage who has passed on who
is above you somewhere else but that's
the equivalent of mimicking a priest and
a sage that means you go to the lesser
God you go to the Ganesh's of the world
you go to the oldest process of the
world yeah well that's what I was
thinking that younger people usually
idolize you know these lesser gods that
you're talking people in their Japanese
right won't you get to be in your 30s or
40s you don't give a shit so what about
the lesser gods but well you still do
twenties yeah but you still you still do
but you're more ignorant of it or you
worship Buddha or something like that
but you know it's I mean this is why we
had Buddha and Muhammad in Jesus and
most of these guys to be humans so we
had these go-betweens
they were also worse than with lesser
cause you're not supposed to worship
Muhammad is a god but you do anyway so
the lesser gods are in front of
important obviously the Catholic Church
figure this out quite early and and turn
them into Saints mm-hmm so their idols
and icons did you turn to me to say
we call we're gonna call this I
chronology in our work to separate from
politics because policies amis is way
more than that it's also the worship of
celebrities and stars and things like
that but it's better than to colleges
iconology so what is an icon ology who
do you look up to as a role model you're
a grown-up and who do you try to mimic
and become like you know who's your role
model who do you train according to its
called Sutra in Buddhism and Hinduism so
you're going to Sutra mode which is
who's your role mode and how can you
make that as perfectly as possible yeah
and obviously do teacher teachers also
who are sort of the teacher as a friend
it's not the same thing as the next
level of Audrianna where the teacher
becomes sort of a transmitter of
something else but on them on on the
sushi on a level the teacher is kind of
like a role model friend yeah I mean
watch Rihanna the teacher is something
quite different than the role model
friend it's a different level of
transmission what we human beings need
somebody to look up to the way chosen
look up to their parents
yeah and that's what we need all the
time because we mimic
we make all the time that's what we
learn things we have to look up you have
to be oh yes looking down and that's
what Saints and lesser gods are for and
it's called iconology and we must
understand that this is fundamental to
human beings into religion and if we
remove that like with donning our
contemporary society then we get rock
stars and sports stars and other idols
and because they failed submissively and
they're not really worth copying then we
all end up in misery like we have now
after 1945 mediocrity and the standard
for human behavior and of course we
don't ask why do you mimic these guys we
just mimic Lee because we're programmed
to find somebody to look up to mimic and
when when they failed at their lives we
have this sort of misery we have right
now we can explain that misery because
these various because we have nobody to
look up to that's very interesting
I mean I've noticed that in my classes
teaching the students don't don't have
you know they have kind of unconscious
role models as you say but they don't
have really powerful
people to look up to yeah I mean at
least youtubers are better the rock
stars in that department because
actually talk to them you listen to them
and that's better so you can although
responsible for their actions but let's
say at least we understand more what
iconology is we understand how important
it is we understand that it's tied into
Normandy ology he started something
fundamentally human and it's called
circular time it's magical and if you
really want to start it and understand
it fully we should study Hinduism right
so but so asterism keeps this the only
thing so a schism does as opposed to
Hinduism is that it switches the
emphases from Normandy ology to ontology
he just switches emphases ok that
priority becomes the phonic that's what
I'm talking about
so Aston is the only phallic modest
religion and what I mean with the
phallic monism is that it's modest in
the sense the universe is one and
everything is interconnected with
everything else
Hinduism believes the same thing
Buddhism believes the same thing
Taoism believes the same thing it's
unthinkable to be dualist in the East
all the older major leaders of the East
are modest and that's exactly where the
win over the Abrahamic faiths today
because we need to get rid of the whole
Gnostic character just useless these
days because you need to go back to the
- the understanding of the world but
with two options what's harassed isn't
does is that it shifts to the phallic
Taoism tries to keep the balance between
the two as young as you
whereas hindusim stays with again more
this case tastes the magical and
Hinduism wisely in a way says that no no
the phallic is for the military the
phallic is for the Yogi's let's keep the
phallic out of the mainstream and let
people go and worship their Ganesha's as
much as they much whereas the Yogi's
mega worshipped the Brahmin only Shiva
hmm yeah or the manifestation of Brahmin
inside isn't that would be Sheela which
is phallus so so they what I've always
argued ever since I started studying so
as soon as in the nineteen eighties was
that was completely misunderstood it was
interpreted by Westerners as a precursor
to Christianity Islam when every outdoor
Astor's it was an Arian into your
in religion it's a so-called religion
it's tantric it's monist it's closely
related taoism buddhism and hinduism and
i'm finally winning this because there's
a whole new generation of special
Iranian American scholars who totally
agree with me who gone back to the
original texts read them in the original
officer language compared to Sanskrit in
India and discovered all the
similarities and the only shift you have
in cerasus or asked this Reformation
1,700 before Christ that enables the
Persian Empire to prosper for the next
fourteen hundred years that revolution
was started by shift from Norman ology
to event ology but the cerasus never
forgot about circular time and it
ignored in Norton or mythology and they
didn't wipe out polytheism they kept it
as a popular folk religion and totally
accepted it which then later Catholicism
had to imitate to save itself right so
that's like I was just thinking that's
the sickness of the West in a way is
this cutting off of polytheism and then
having it be repressed
having been repressed and then and then
manifest itself as pop stars and rather
than having it being taken seriously
well it's kind of if you mix sutra and
tantra you kill both wouldn't you agree
with that you got to keep Sutra Tantra
separate understand them separately mmm
because our sutures a foundation of
Tantra so even even if it is no my
knowledge is a foundation of an ontology
ok matriarchy is the foundational
patriarchy mm-hmm sure circular time is
the foundation before we can have a dare
to think linear time slow we have to
start there yeah so North the real
understanding religion so it's only
because they settled down that we can
start to imagine that what was
previously something the Mystics don't
would the shaman's don't would and that
possibly could be an idea of the
military or the priests could deal with
southern are we settle down this becomes
the dominant mode who can actually
aspire to and what this does is that it
creates the first theory of empire it
creates the idea that you can have
several different peoples so
different you know clients and tribes
even nations living together under one
roof mm-hmm that would have been
unthinkable unless you had presented of
ontology as a superior theory to the
mythology like okay we don't know but
already so far in history we'll keep it
as a popular engine but it when it comes
to the vision and the strategy of
society as a whole which is an imperial
theory the name of that religion would
be an ontology that's what's our
estimates the first religion probably
still the only gene that's a truly
Imperial digit that's also why it's the
foundation for universal human rights
and so what the purse is do is that they
establish this right I'm just laughing
because that's so against the grain of
how people think these days because
imperialism is is considered to be a
great evil right and that's ridiculous
impurity is a beautiful idea but today
how are we gonna save the damn planet
unless we go Imperial seriously
well Imperial just means very big and
very great and the greatest possible
well we've reached the end of the planet
anyway we reach certain end points in
history we went to the moon in 1969 it
was a disaster there was nothing there
because we territorially expanded and
killed each other and across the entire
planet up until that point and that's
the second body feels uncomfortable the
territorial expansion after 1969 yeah
because we realized that oh there was
nothing there to go to like Heidegger
rooty 1958 what the satellites told us
was that who you were the planet we
lived on and there was nothing else for
us to find his face and that territorial
expansion had come to an end
mmm-hmm so we really know what's Erastus
revolution did three thousand seven
years ago is we're now kicking the
second gear of that revolution the
second gear of that revolution is that
well now we have no more territory to
expand into even if it permanent to
settle and colonize because the name for
being a nomad while you still have a
permanent settlement is colonization
mmm-hmm colonization is continent yeah
that means we have nowhere else to go
than our ideas we have to go more event
illogical not less so a return to pure
numerology to return to paganism is
absolutely impossible we've been forced
to rethink an ontology and that's why
I'm all for it so Aston Renaissance in
the sense that if you go back to the
origin of the Abrahamic faiths and if
you go back to the origin of Tantra in
the east authentic monism which is my
favorite you go to the we find a common
thread here and that's along the Silk
Road and it's Persia and it's a Persian
Empire is a beautiful place to start to
then realize when the Chinese mimicked
the Persians and did right and be wrong
well the Gipp just mimic the Persians
and did right did wrong and we're
certainly eventually the Arabs and the
Europeans they make the person be very
wrong so this is why I think today to
understand make a comparative analysis
of American China today would be the
equal of taking antiquity you know why
arguing we don't for variety all the
time that he sees too much we found of
the axial age I think actually I wanted
to come to the Greeks a little bitter or
yeah yeah yeah but when we come to and
we come to the axial age when created
abundance we have a period of peace and
we've learned to associate periods of
peace and prosperity and abundance with
thinking right hold on the axial age is
a period of peace and abundance wasn't
it a period of kind of like
comparatively absolutely yes so that's
exactly why there were so many thinkers
around people who walked around and they
had gurus all over the place who were
very self-indulgent and narcissistic in
front of themselves I don't hold these
guys as highly as guys the John farver I
could do I don't know how to hold the
Great Society as it does I think the
really interesting shit happened before
that during the Bronze Age and I think
that's what we need to go back and make
a comparative study Persian Egypt back
then in American China today you know I
think America is in a big crisis and
it's heading in the wrong direction but
it's got one beautiful thing to say it's
and it's called the Constitution
why because the Constitution is
fundamentally no mine illogical hmm it's
built in a triad it's built on plurality
yeah so American culture is built on
plurality freedom of speech you know and
and this is the opposite of China
Chinese today's Egypt that is mimicked
America but if used to mimic and taking
the US Constitution the problem would
shine of the problem the rest of our
house in China is that we love Taiwan
would love Hong Kong we love the excel
time ease we think they're fantastic
the problem with China itself is that
it's communist and it's wrong as a
dictatorship one-man rule she'd be the
originator of that idea Zack Martin in
Egypt mm-hmm that's 1300 before Christ
so that's obviously 400 years after the
surest a revolution in Persian and after
the rest literally just made its mark in
the Middle East
so what Norton is doing in Egypt he's
tried to mimic what the persons have
achieved but he does that as a one-man
dictatorship
mm-hmm big mistake mm-hmm cuz you need
us yeah he's not as arrested he doesn't
understand you need to split the fallacy
need to have a strong majority in a
society mm-hm you need to have the match
or key that holds the pad turkey
responsible for its delivery so you have
reproduction in place and you can then
have reincarnation ideas and policies
and whatever you like within the matter
key but on top of that type of
patriarchy and the Tetrarchy is run by
split fella so you separate them all
there in the shop you separately chief
Kent and the priest that's what the
persons were adamant about they're
adamant he stops fighting what's a
little silastic must not be the same
person the Egyptians did not understand
this but not uncreated what's exactly
the the precursor to today's seeing
thing dictatorship in China mm-hmm and
he failed he stayed in power until they
died his son Tutankhamun inherited and
eventually Tutankhamun was killed by the
priests mm-hmm it's basically
totalitarianism I mean yeah and it's
very very like this is the origin of
Judaism
it's very likely that I wouldn't say
Judaism is atavism which was like that
is religion I would say it's a post
Adventist cult in Egypt and if Moses
existed which is likely at least he
existed then Moses was an Egyptian who
led an Egyptian cult out of Egypt about
300 years later so and 1700 before
Christ again so roster a 1300 for Christ
you get it Norton you got the failure
Tutankhamun and he's being killed by the
priests hey I'm just this remind you of
Christ in the cross later right
mimicking again so the origin of Judaism
the origin of Christianity are very
similar it starts with the priests
killing the God hmm the man God so this
is this is what they do in Egypt and we
don't know exactly how this fight about
but I'm sorry with Cain killing it yeah
a post act and his cult eventually
leaves Egypt in the rise eventually in
Babylon he babbled only gets mixed with
Taurus on is Amman we talk to you you
and I talked a lot about the love
relationship needs or Astin ISM and
Judaism and the tragedy why Iran and
Israel are not allies today because
historically Persia and Israel opposed
it allies and and would happen with the
Soros Jones and the Jews is that source
has found an Egyptian cult that was sort
of independent a very urban in Babylon
and they loved them and they sponsored
the Jews to go back and rebuild the
temple in Jerusalem and thereby create a
proper nation inside the Persian Empire
this is the birth of nationalism
nationalism is the result imperialism
not the other way around
mmm-hmm Elizabeth's older than
nationalism Oh interesting
hmm I thought yeah and that's acceptable
anti-semitism is different from other
forms of racism because it's
fundamentally a combined nation and
religion ending at the end of the day
we've never had a better nation than
Israel throughout human history
the nation of Israel the nation of the
Jews of the Hebrews has been totally
superior to any other nationality before
or after for that matter because it is
the fundamental unification of nation
and religion church and state are not
separated in Judaism and that's the
beauty of it the zorathus didn't
separate them either they separated
polytheism for monitors and allowed both
hmm a state India Judaism's problem some
kind of separation has to take place but
yes Judas is probably started to try to
kill its magical religion and forth only
phallic religion on to the Hebrews but
at least it was split we got the split
between Java and L within Judaism every
Jewish mystic would agree and that is
accepting what the either inherited from
the persons or picked up for the persons
or they've understood after left Egypt
but this was a necessity that's exactly
why the Jews say you cannot say God's
name because you say goes they be
discovered their several names to God
and they're actually different different
faces to God if different so this is the
strength of Judah somebody solves its
weakness I would say it can only ever be
a national religion it can never be an
imperialism because it doesn't
understand that NAT Turkey needs to be
respected as a cold religion with
patriarchy hmm the phallic and the
magical have to be there together this
is the beauty of India and Iran hmm I
would say that's kind of though that's
kind of the Jewish Christian split as
well that you're describing yeah
Jonah has a similar problem to to
Christianity in that split up church and
state and it did so because Confucius
eventually became the state and taoism
buddhism shared the role of the religion
in China and the problem with that is
that statehood is not under religious
jurisdiction that means you could have
dictators like champagne and at the end
of the day if the religion controls a
society you must let have a dictator you
must understand that you split the rule
into two and eventually into three
originally two three what do you mean
well it's Authority know what the third
is the matriarchy
oh I see okay okay okay so if you look
if you look at the rest in religion it
has odor and it has master and then it
has to society community in itself the
dog has to go to summer heat if you want
to bring her into it but that's the folk
religion aspect of it we don't need that
because it's a fairly college and it
puts you on the move the way so raster
woman would describe it is that she
would say that religion in our
interestin ism is for the men and women
reap the benefits from it what you
cannot have those you cannot have
religion only for women but not for men
hmm isn't that ironic interesting so
what you get them is that Christianity
mimics Judaism and mimics Judaism and
tries to go universal and what
eventually borrow those from surrounds
the understanding if you split God into
two and eventually to three you get a
try it as much more stable over time and
it's this act about the Trinity Trinity
done it and that's the great thing with
Christianity is that it separates Father
Son and spirit now spirit was way to
wait for people to understand so when
you finally arrived with the
polytheistic version of Christianity
when Christianity gets iconology the
Virgin Mary and the Jesus child arrive
in a big way mm-hmm and they become a
turkey within Christianity mm-hmm and
then you keep the father in the Sun and
you turn the Holy Spirit into the
congregation itself the strength of
Christianity is it's no matter logical
structure that's why it was so stable
and spin so successful over time but the
problem is it's built on a mimicking of
the birth of Judaism and and the
allusion here is that if you have a
scapegoat on the cross micronesia riser
if you get a scapegoat on the cross
skateboarding's once and for all over
and history has changed forever
mm-hmm now if that didn't happen
mm-hmm that did happen what happened is
that well it doesn't happen at I mean
George theory it it happens gradually
over a long long period of time not like
there's no oh we scapegoat more than
ever in contemporary society and if we
left Christianity it's come back in a
big way I mean what are these speech
polices we got everywhere these days you
judge you forever to eternal damnation
just for using the wrong word
hey we skate book more than ever we got
lynch mobs all over the place in
American Europe today we have not
learned a single thing about putting the
scapegoat on the cross in the ghetto
it's kid going T so hero is
fundamentally wrong it failed but it
also failed because in the fifth century
seanica should he just you know kept his
magical aspects kept stay with the
Virgin Mary and the Jesus child and then
added a military religion which he could
have done with Mithraism added the
military legion on top of that for for
the military for the priests to run how
do you need chances of center because
the Roman Empire was a dictatorship
again the problem is always
dictatorships those dictatorship you
could only get one throne in Rome and it
became a strong between the Christians
let me throw the quiz just one and
within the next 50 years me as it was
swept off the planet it always just
swept off the earth and we were laugh to
Christianity is the only religion and
since then the West has proudly declared
that we managed to separate church and
state isn't that wonderful
but a reality we never managed to settle
down that is Nietzsche's death of God
isn't it and yes sadly because we get a
state a patriarchal state we get a
military and we get even a priesthood
called politics
thanks without religion and the reason
why the waste eventually conquer the
rest of planet and then plundered it and
brought us almost extinction so the
death of God I'm sorry to drop the death
of God is the death of of the fellows in
the Sun yes yes yes exactly I never
thought of it that way
um no ad suggest a phallus it happens
right in the fifth century we need to go
about that mean we don't say the kiss
now I've done this and did his little
it's incredibly dark book is prophetic
unfortunates it's coming true but it did
it a little bit oh we discusses in
detail but we discuss in vanilla tea as
a problem after 1945 but in reality the
problem is very well we're did use 1945
what's the word use what was the
infantile essential that you said
incentive infant early infantilism the
effect infantilization contemporary
society and their lack of adult to it
you know Jordan Peter says repeated
problem starts already 1945 and it
explodes in the 1950s and exposed with
the pop cultural icon ology again of the
failed rock star and the hippies and
everything and and it moved us away from
the focus on phallic addition Australia
like Peter Thiel and many guys are
pointing out right now this is the
ultimate failure of the West but it goes
back further it goes back to
Christianity lacking in the respect to
being a phallic religion it's a non
fallibilism obviously if you put the guy
on the cross and he dies young you don't
even know they've had a sex life or not
you obviously killed the file is already
there so they didn't eat cheese right
but the death of Christ is historically
speaking now we see the long-term
effects is the death of the phallus the
death of the phallic God and we can't do
without Father God cannot do without the
father God we get how much so
we're there now an apocalyptic times in
that sense where I see I think we see
the end of Islam and the end of
Christianity mythic sacrum of these two
religions are gone fundamentalist and
gone aggressive and against each other
and they're trying to make it look as if
they literally just left a croissant in
Islam but if they want to go eventually
towards Armageddon and try to kill each
other then so be it
I I think this is the end game for
Christianity and Islam because these
religions removed the barred absolute
and and that was a big big mistake and
we need to go back to reimbursed and
religion fundamentally reinstate the
part absolute when I hear you say that I
feel somewhat skeptical that these
religions could just end they just kind
of keep going don't they I mean no
didn't they be reformed rather than like
oh no 95% of Swedes have told the
Christian Church to fuck off and die
right okay I think what's happening
countries but they've all become they've
all become secularists atheists I've
been feminists and they're not
Christians any longer that's for sure
they've gone back into some kind of
weird pagan apocalyptic mode right so
that know at the end of the day we have
to take the larger historical picture
mm-hmm we have to understand human
beings as the salt the size of that is
sociology the narrative for that is
numerology is the story of circular time
and and this is how we live for about 60
to 70 thousand years and our genes were
shaped during that period now it didn't
happen ten thousand years
ago is that a mimetic revolution get
started we have not changed biologically
the last 10,000 years rather are
bringing some shrunk and they become
were stupid but technology exploded and
we took knowledge I was a culture
exploded and that happened because we
settled permanently was settled
permanently because of written language
to begin with that meant the idea of
ontology could take root and it did in
certain parts of the world and so raster
was unique probably the smartest guy
ever when he formulated a theory on EV
ontology 3700 gothis you can read it if
you can read the original with some
language even better because the English
translations are full of mistakes but
when you go into the understanding or
what Saurashtra means and the religion
he wants to create that it comes
furnished credibly which is like a state
of a term renewal constant renewal this
is the idea of civilization itself and
so we can improve things the Sun can
live better than the father did and
because the Sun creates a better world
and the father could then the daughter
can live a better life from the mother
can this means we move from Norman ology
to EV ontology and from then on religion
becomes more important than spirituality
the fact that men are lead is more
important than the women are so you said
that you thought that spirituality is
feminine how many works in any case
women do spirituality wonderfully they
do it all the time they did the mother
teaches the daughter how to become a
proper woman if they can only do that
are allowed to do that the way they
should and could that then there's no
problem that the problem is with the man
and the problem that's what we confused
and we talked about patch our keys which
negative terms and things like today
because the men are cookies because it
was the man who we left without a
religion and not only did we live
without religion the west we left we
left them with a complete
misunderstanding a religion called Islam
south of the Mediterranean
because Islam is the absolute mimicking
of Judas and mimicking Zoroastrianism it
says like okay take it can you just take
a final collision and worship the
military and forget about priests and
they'd have the military
for the world and with no respect for
you know where you're gonna arrive
Mohammed was a military genius but a
religious of theological disaster that's
that's how I really stopped and that's
the problem with the storm and and the
reason of course is because I've started
person history in detail and the whole
new generation I'm Iranian American
stories especially now and you Indian
historians are also discovering that
it's very important to start the
Sassanid Empire the last person Empire
before the the Persian Empire imploded
in the 6th century and Stasi phone fell
to an Arab relation we must understand
that it was hit by plague and you had
several wars against the Christians so
bazaars and stress afford a constant
warfare with each other they're both
really tired and exhausted
they ruined all of us you know and so
the Arab invasion came from the south
their invasion was of course sponsored
by Persians were opposed to the Sassanid
Empire so would happen in the Sassanid
Empire was there were several new sets
and cults were loads of sets and cult
flourishing in the Middle East this was
at the same time as Christianity came
along Christianity became power in the
Roman Empire but in the in the Persian
Empire next door the two most popular
ideas were presented by two guys called
Manny and mustard and if you study the
history IDs you know these guys are
quite important without money as
Manichean which was an incredibly
popular cult widespread the Central
Asian Americans there wouldn't be an
August in August even was Boris mighty
can he officially pronounce us of
Christian before he died but with
Augustine came on automatic Ian's ideas
into Christianity and a sense for
Christianity became Gnostic after that
without Augustine you would never have
the separation of churches think the way
yeah so I think with Augustine
Christianity became religion or boys and
women no and the men and the daughters
were forgettin
forgotten it was all about boys and
women and and the agnostic religion
returning to is that Manny Kasem was
transferred into Christianity and the
other cult we would possibly even work
with
mastic I called in the Persian Empire
mastic was incredibly charismatic
communists he was by far the first
communist Stalin loved him by the way
and installed and decided to give the
Soviet Union the red flag he borrowed
the red collar from the master cons of
the person so the master Kaiser Gnostics
they believed that the soul was way
higher than the body and the soul and
body should be separated man even more
so with mass that's versatile that was
to create a communist utopia and he went
after just about everybody who forced
the upper class in the lower classes to
marry each other he distributed you know
the income dispersed it equal equal
outcome for everybody rather than equal
opportunity the idea of equal outcome
but it starts in master now that old
sounded nice didn't it I think any
Bernie Sanders fan today probably loves
these ideas and his socialist or
communist I love these ideas forever the
problem is is that it creates complete
utter havoc and the Persian Empire
almost fell apart and finally was
thesaurus term Oh beds not thesaurus
Kinshasa was the priests now the
generation was the priests we decided to
go after Mao stock and money and
especially went after masters and they
basically massacred the Master kites
knowing that if Gnosticism sentence and
he takes over the Empire the Empire will
be over and people will do the fucked up
hmm so you know back in those days so
you know so you have the invasion of
Gnostic dualism into Christianity and
into Zoroastrian societies well and what
then happen was that big Gnostics
settled on the arab peninsula and that
became Islam Islam's origin is mastic
ISM that's exactly why Islam and
socialism and communism so much in
common
look at the Middle East it switched from
socialism to Islamism in less than ten
years why is that so easy because that
because the idea of the umma the only
Congregational community that works in
the Arab world the Islamic Ummah is
identical to the socialist commune it's
the same idea
well so this is the problem
we known ever since that yeah that's a
political alternative it's okay we can
have social democracy but if you
installed masochism as a dictatorship
you get Stalinism mmm yeah right
so I would say that what we inherited
from the Middle East and Europe is only
a child of the Middle East Europe has
ever been mimicking the Middle East
Middle East is the birth of civilization
and everything you have constantly lists
so if we look at these creatures these
guys at naught and unmask dog and look
at the dangers of dictatorship and
totalitarianism and authoritarianism
what we inherited eventually in Europe
starting libros so in the 18th century
and he's found deceased Avenger led to
the French Revolution of jacobeans that
later became Marxism but Marx of course
had a different idea that also but he
was probably a bit naive in what we
eventually ended up with was of course
Hitler and Stalin and Mao and Pol Pot
and these dictators are all mimicking it
not on mass sucking different variations
of so they're located between these guys
and we haven't learned the lesson that
the what religion was meant to do was
prevent patriarchy from becoming a
dictatorship that is fundamentally what
religion does well religion does not
allow to cater ship mm-hmm religion is
the name of the separation of powers
that's great I never thought of that
before that's why I love the US
Constitution because the US Constitution
both has heritage going all the way back
to the rationalism and going back to the
best part of Christianity it mimics the
triad here so it mimics the Trinity of
Christianity and it certainly mimics to
try it that was preached it taught by
the surest just like easy if the guys
get their shit together and the priests
and the chief can lead the tribe on the
move and the woman can deliver the
children at the other end so Patrick a
metric at work the way you've done that
use Constitution you start to replace
the chief time with the precedent it's
an excessive power you replace the
priest with the Congress a legislative
power they set the law for priests to
the regulations please said that you
must operate within this regulation and
then you got a match are you holding the
other two guys responsible and it's
called the Supreme Court
that's the elders of America right I
love the US Constitution like the talk
will did now think of ultimately he will
save America it was safe probably
America hopefully from war and
definitely from becoming a dictatorship
and that's why I put you great hopes to
America and what I love guys like Peter
Thiel and these guys out there right now
trying now to to reformulate a fan
equation for America and wake America up
because America has been asleep for the
last 40 or 50 years to become degenerate
decadent and and and it's at a very very
dangerous place now and also become much
more than just and it should have been
obviously that is incredibly frustrating
too but that's only that's what happens
when the society becomes more decadent
and and people don't care about their
own people anymore the American Dream is
dead and over and I think what Peter
days trying to do is he's reading Col
Smith is reading the astrology reading
these guys you and I really need some
Frawley young and we arrived at the same
place and Jordan Peters and obviously we
read Nietzsche Freud a young to arrive
at the same place too